你要是在东部时间上午十点十一点左右用FR24看过北大西洋上空
If you’ve ever looked at a flight tracker sometime around 10 or 11 pm eastern
你会注意到这些飞机都排好长队一路飞往欧洲
you might have noticed something—perfect lines of planes stretching all the way to Europe.
而它们只是每天横跨北大西洋的两千趟航班中的一部分
These are just some of the over 2,000 daily flights that cross the Northern Atlantic.
这么多航班可得管好。这是纽约到伦敦的直线距离
With so many flights, there just has to be organization. This is the most direct route from New York to London.
你可能以为是这才是“直线”，错咧
You may think it’s this, a straight line, but that straight line isn’t actually a straight line.
这条曲线是“直的”，因为甭管有些神棍怎么想，地球是圆的
This curved line is a straight line because, despite what some may think, the earth is curved.
纽约到伦敦可能没这么直观
From New York to London the curve you see on a flat map isn’t too extreme, but in
但长一点，比如纽约到曼谷，在地球表面的直线距离
the case of a longer flight, such as from New York to Bangkok, the most direct route
不是这条，而是这条，横穿北极点。从北极点俯视图看的话更明显
is not this, but this—straight over the North Pole. It makes more since if you look at a north-pole oriented map.
如果你从亚特兰大到伦敦画一条直线
If you draw the most direct route between Atlanta and London
你会看到这条线几乎经过了东海岸所有大型国际机场
you’ll see that it passes over every major east coast international airport.
说明亚特兰大的欧洲航班的路线和
That means that planes from Atlanta to Europe travel on the exact same route as planes from
从夏洛特、华盛顿、巴尔的摩、费城、纽约、波士顿的路线是一样的
Charlotte, Washington, Baltimore, Philadelphia, New York and Boston.
这些横跨大西洋的航班主要在东部时间晚上六点到八点起飞，一大早在欧洲降落
All these transatlantic planes typically leave between 6-8 pm Eastern to time their arrival for early morning in Europe.
说明同一路线、同时可能有上百架飞机
This means that there are potentially hundreds of planes all going the exact same route at the exact same time.
北大西洋上空还有“高速气流”
The North Atlantic also has something known as the Jet Stream.
当中的西风速度大约每小时110英里(177公里、96海里)，飞机借着它能省很多时间
These easterly winds average around 110 mph and if planes fly in them, they can cut hours of their travel time,
然而，这条风带最强范围只有160公里宽、5公里高
however, the winds are only strongest in a line three miles high (5 km) and 100 miles (160 km) wide.
这又压缩了航路间距
That further concentrates the flights.
平均算来，纽约飞伦敦要花6小时15分钟
On average, an eastbound transatlantic flight from New York to London takes about 6 hours and 15 minutes.
飞回来则要顶着气流，飞行时间超过7小时
Coming back against the jet stream, the same flight takes over 7 hours.
有时风还能更大，比如在2015年1月8日
Sometimes, the winds can be even more active such as on January 8th, 2015 when British
英航114航班，纽约飞伦敦，只花了5小时16分钟，创造了新的民航亚音速客机的记录
Airways flight 114 flew from New York to London in only 5 hours and 16 minutes—a new record for a commercial subsonic plane.
当天高速气流时速超过每小时200英里(320公里、174海里)，那架波音777
On that day, the jet stream was blowing over 200 mph (320 km/h) and the Boeing 777 reached
(地速)达到了每小时745英里(1200公里，647海里)，只比地面静风音速慢25km/h
a speed of 745 mph (1200 km/h) —only 16 mph (25 km/h) below the sound barrier.
如果风能让飞机少飞一小时，波音777每小时耗油2700加仑(10200升)
So when winds can cut an hour off a flight and a 777 burns 2,700 gallons (10,200 liters)
航空燃油每加仑1.89美元，那就为航司省下5103美元，就看你在哪个区域飞了
of fuel per hour and jet fuel costs $1.89 per gallon, that’s a $5,103 difference between being in the right, and the wrong winds.
希望你能知道这点非常重要
Hopefully you now see why this is important.
同一航线上有这么多飞机，通常来说问题不大
So there are all these planes that are flying the exact same route, but usually that’s no problem.
北美最忙航线，纽约到芝加哥，每天100趟航班
The busiest route in North America, New York to Chicago, sees over 100 flights per day
早晚高峰每五分钟一趟，它们也是都飞直线
leaving as frequently as every five minutes during the morning and evening rush and these planes just fly the most efficient route.
飞之前，航线规划会和空管一起定好航线，在飞行中
Before the flight, route planners file a plan with air traffic control and during the flight
空管用一些办法引导飞机前后间距最小的时候只有5海里
they’re just directed by air traffic control in a way that keeps them 5 nautical miles from other planes.
纽约飞芝加哥与飞伦敦的区别在于，北大西洋上空没有雷达
The difference between New York to Chicago and New York to London is that, over the North Atlantic, there is no radar.
雷达只能覆盖到海岸边250英里远。但横跨大西洋要飞上千英里
You see, radar only extends about 250 miles offshore. Transatlantic planes can be more than a thousand miles from shore.
所以每天早上，位于纽芬兰岛甘德市的甘德空管中心
That’s why every morning, the route planners at Gander Air Traffic Control Center in Gander, Newfoundland
会发布当日的北大西洋航路
publish the days North Atlantic Tracks.
前一晚，每家要在第二天飞跃大西洋的航司
The night before, every airline that will fly across the atlantic the following day
向甘德提交一份“首选航路信息”，告诉他们航司最想沿着哪条航线飞
sends Gander a Preferred Route Message indicating what they think the best route will be.
多数情况，甘德中心会同意这些请求，然后设计十多条航路
For the most part, Gander center follows these requests and creates a set of 10 or so routes.
这些航路保证尽可能多的飞机沿着尽可能高效的路线飞往欧洲
These tracks attempt to get the most amount of planes on the most efficient route to Europe.
这些路线标记规则，从南往北数，最南边的代号Z，然后是Y
The tracks are labeled: Zulu being the southernmost route, Yankee being the second southernmost,
接着是X、W以此类推，接下来我举个例子
then Xray, then Whisky, and so on and so forth. Here’s how a flight on the tracks works.
不过提前说下，接下来要有点专业了。假如我们要从纽约飞巴黎
And I’ll warn you, this is when the video gets technical. Let’s say we’re going from New York to Paris.
预定起飞前半小时，机长向空管请求往加拿大纽芬兰飞
Around half an hour before scheduled departure, the captain talks to normal air traffic control
to request clearance for the route up to around Newfoundland, Canada.
多数情况我们的请求得到许可，又过一会起飞了
In most cases clearance is given, and soon after we’ll take off.
等飞机快要飞过圣劳伦斯湾，飞行员开始请求TA想要的北大西洋航路
About when the plane crosses the Gulf of St Lawrence, the pilot will request the North Atlantic Track that he or she desires.
这是今日飞跃大西洋的路线信息
Here’s today’s message describing the day’s routes over the Atlantic.
机长看过后，决定请求路线W
After looking over this, the pilot decides to request track Whisky.
意思是目前我们要先飞RAFIN航点，即路线W的起始点
That means that, at least for now, we’ll head towards the RAFIN waypoint, our oceanic entry point.
航点就是用来导航的点
Waypoints are fixed spots that are used for flight navigation.
方便空管和飞行员在无线电里交流，因为说坐标的话太麻烦了
These are much easier for Air Traffic Control to communicate to pilots than map coordinates when speaking over radio.
有些航点名称很有意思，新罕布什尔州莱巴嫩北部有三个点连起来意思是汉堡、薯条
Occasionally you’ll see some creatively named waypoints. Just north of Lebanon, New Hampshire are HAMMM, BURGR, and FRYYS.
堪萨斯城机场进近上，你们自己看吧我都饿了
On approach to Kansas City Airport there’s SPICY BARBQ TERKY SMOKE RIBBS.
芝加哥两个航点名字是他们两个棒球队：芝加哥小熊队(Cubs)和芝加哥熊队(Bears)
这里YouTuber说错成波士顿 不过波士顿也有航点用他们的球队命名
Boston has two waypoints in support of their sports teams, the KUBBS and BEARS.
有的航点则很严肃。华盛顿里根国际机场北部进近
Some waypoint names are more somber. On the northern approach route to Washington Regan National Airport,
离911事件中撞五角大楼的地方只有几英里，航点连起来就是“我们永远不会忘记9月11日”
just miles away from where a plane hit the Pentagon on 9/11, the waypoints read WEEEE WLLLL NEVVR FORGT SEP11.
由于北大西洋航路每天都在变，NOTAM只给出北大西洋航路的起点和终点
NOTAM是英语“给飞行员通知”(Notice To Airmen)的缩写
Since the North Atlantic Tracks change every day, the NOTAM just gives entry and exit waypoints,
和中间的坐标
and then coordinates for the route in between.
而路线坐标是在飞机起飞前早已设定好的
Since the track coordinates are pre-programed into the autopilot before take-off, there’s
也就没必要给它们挨个起名字了
no reason to name them as waypoints since they won’t be given over radio.
在刚刚的例子里，我们请求路线W，多数情况下甘德
In the case of this flight, we’re REQUESTING track WHISKY and, more than likely, Gander
空管中心会允许，但也有些情况下他们会让我们走别的航路
Control Center will give permission, although, sometimes they’ll tell us to take a different track,
通常因为我们与其他飞机距离小于最小间隔
usually because we’re closer to another plane than the minimum separation distance.
因为在北大西洋上空知道飞机位置很难
Since it’s much more difficult to know where planes are over the North Atlantic,
所以他们间隔要求是15分钟——大约140英里(225公里、122海里)——远大于有雷达时的5海里
they're required to be 15 minutes separated—about 140 miles—rather than the normal 5 miles in areas with radar coverage.
假如我们获准了，我们就往RAFIN航点飞，然后确认
Assuming we’re granted clearance, we’ll head towards RAFIN waypoint and make sure
卫星通讯系统正常，然后检查
that our satellite communication systems are working, then we’ll check to see if the
高频无线电正常——这是其他通讯设备失效时的备份
High Frequency Radio is working—a backup in case other communications go down.
几分钟后，通过RAFIN点后，空管会说
Minutes later, just after passing RAFIN waypoint, the controller will say
“雷达服务终止，晚安”，然后我们就自己飞了
“radar services terminated, have a good night,” and then we’re on our own.
整条航路早已写进了自动驾驶，所以飞行员啥都不用干，等着就行
All the North Atlantic Tracks are preloaded onto autopilot, so there’s nothing really to do except wait.
过了西经30度，我们离欧洲越来越近了，进入Shanwick区域空域
When we we hit 30 west, we enter the Shanwick airspace approaching Western Europe.
无线电调到Shanwick的频率，再飞一小时到北大西洋航路终点——
We switch our radios to Shanwick’s frequency, then fly a few more hours to our Oceanic Exit
GUNSO航点——说明我们成功飞跃北大西洋了
Point—GUNSO waypoint—meaning we’ve successfully traversed the Northern Atlantic.